（春野はるのサクラ）ハア ハア…
あっ はっ…
あれが本体？
That's his real body.
After twenty years,
what say we face each other?
（チヨ）20年ぶりに
まみえようではないか
（テマリ）ん…
What took you so long?
（カンクロウ）遅かったな
（テマリ）ハッ…
これでも飛ばして帰ってきたんだ
But I flew back as quickly
as I could.
More to the point,
それより 国境警備の代役
よこすのが遅すぎだぞ
you took too long to send over
a substitute border guard.
Your planning was bad.
（テマリ）お前の手はずが悪い
これでも 病み上がりに
お前のわがまま聞いてやったんだ
That's no way to show
your appreciation.
I carried out your selfish request
despite recovering from an illness.
その言いぐさは ねえじゃん
（舌打ち）
（テマリ）はあ…
ふん！
さて 行くか
Well... Shall we get going?
Yeah.
ああ
Yes, sir!
（マツリ）はい
あっ
It can still move?!
（サクラ）まだ動くの？
As I thought.
（サソリ）やっぱりな
さすが 俺のババアなだけはある
Just what I'd expect
from my old grandma.
どうりで この小娘まで
俺の仕込みをかわせたわけだ
No wonder this little girl was able
to dodge my hidden weapons.
After all, the old grandma who can see
past my attacks was controlling
俺の攻撃を見切れるババアが
傀儡くぐつの術のチャクラ糸で
小娘を操ってたんだからな
the little girl with Chakra threads
used for the Puppet Master Jutsu.
He found out.
（サクラ）バレた
（サソリ）それにだ
What's more, you were so kind as to
attach threads of Chakra to Hiruko's tail.
ご丁寧に ヒルコの尾にまで
チャクラ糸を
しかし 尾の動きを止められて
初めて気づかされるとはな
But to think that I'd notice it
after the tail's motion had been
brought to a halt...
（サソリ）最初に
クナイで攻撃したときだろう
It was when you first attacked
with the Kunai Knife, wasn't it?
クナイに付いていたチャクラ糸を
Threads of Chakra attached
to the Kunai Knife
latched onto the tail
when it repelled the Kunai Knife.
クナイをはじいた尾に 付け替えた
I suppressed my Chakra as much
as possible so as not to be seen,
ほう 目に見えぬよう
チャクラを ギリギリまで
抑えていたというのに
and yet you still figured it out.
I'm amazed.
よく分かったな
なっ…
（サソリ）そりゃそうだろ
But of course.
傀儡遊びを 俺にたたき込んだのは
ほかでもない…
After all, the one who hammered
the principles of puppetry into me was...
none other than you.
あんただぜ
Yes.
（チヨ）ああ
But the show ends today.
じゃが 遊びはきょうで終わりじゃ
That is my intention as well.
（サソリ）こっちも そのつもりだ
あっ…
（サソリ）
さあて そう簡単にいくかな？
Well then, will things proceed
as simply as that, I wonder...
チヨバア様よ
Grandmother Chiyo...?
チヨバア様
Grandmother Chiyo?
こいつが…
Is he... Is he Sasori?
こいつが サソリ？
What is going on?
どういうことじゃ
He's just as he was before...
He hasn't aged a bit.
（チヨ）
昔のまま 年を取っておらぬ
What's going on?!
（サクラ）どういうこと？
サソリは 20年も前に
砂隠すながくれを抜けたって
I was told Sasori broke off from
the Hidden Sand 20 years ago...
He couldn't be that young.
こんなに若いはずが…
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Sasori's Real Face
（うずまきナルト）クソ！
Damn it...!
（はたけカカシ）
さっき 中から聞こえてきた音は
The sound that I heard coming
from inside just a while ago...
すでに 戦闘が
始まっているのは確かだ
There's no doubt that
the battle has already begun.
状況を把握しておきたいところだが
I'd like to get a grasp
of the situation, but...
（ナルト）てめえ！
我愛羅があらを返せってばよ
You! Return Gaara to us!
（デイダラ）サソリの旦那が
中の連中を始末するのも
It's only a matter of time
before my man Sasori does away
with the group inside.
時間の問題だな うん
If my man comes out,
旦那に出てこられると
then the whole point of using this one
to draw out the Jinchuriki will be lost.
こいつを使って 人柱力じんちゅうりきを
誘い出した意味がなくなるな
（ナルト）うっ… 野郎
You jerk!
I won't let you get away.
逃がしゃしねえ！
待ちやがれ！
Hold it right there!
（カカシ）ナルト 待て！
Naruto, wait a minute!
えい カカシ先生は
サクラちゃんのほうを頼むってばよ
Kakashi-sensei,
you go look after Sakura-chan!
（カカシ）ったく…
Good grief.
（無線のスイッチ音）
（カカシ）ガイ
Guy, how are conditions
over there?
そちらの状況は？
（マイト･ガイ）うお！
（ガイ）はあ－！
どっ…
ハア ハア…
すまぬ カカシ
Sorry Kakashi, it looks like things
will still take a while over here.
こっちは まだ少しかかりそうだ
（日向ひゅうがネジ）ハア ハア…
（ネジ）ええい！
回天かいてん！
Rotation.
If detaining someone is your objective,
there's no better way than this.
足止めが目的なら
これ以上はない方法だな
（テンテン）ハア ハア…
相手が 自分と全く同じ能力を
持ってるなら…
If your opponent has exactly
the same abilities as you do...
（ロック･リー）そう簡単に
けりはつきそうもありませんね
It probably won't be that easy
to bring matters to a close.
お見事です
Splendid move, Imposter.
偽物君
（カカシ）
クソっ 援護は当分 無理か
Damn... Looks like it's impossible to
expect back-up for a while.
サクラ チヨバア様
Sakura, Grandmother Chiyo,
hold down the fort a bit longer!
もう少し ふんばってくれよ
絶対ぜってえ 逃がさねえ！
There's no way I'm going
to let you get away!
They're coming, aren't they?
（デイダラ）来てるな うん
しっかり ついてこいよ
Better keep up!
そしたら
ちゃんと始末してやるからな うん
And then,
I will settle matters properly...
止まれ！
Stop!
うっ…
どうした？ カンクロウ
What's wrong, Kankuro?
ここで休憩をとる
We'll rest here.
何？ どういうことだ カンクロウ
What?! What do you think
you're doing, Kankuro?!
こんなところで
ちんたら休んでる暇などない
There's no time to rest easy
in a situation like this!
そう焦るなって
Don't be so impatient...
That's not like you, Sis.
いつもの姉貴らしくないじゃん
あっ はっ…
（マツリ）
申し訳ありません テマリさん
I'm sorry, Temari-san.
（砂すなの里さとの忍）ちょっと…
ちょっと休めば すぐ走れます
Just a little while...
If we rest just a little while,
we'll be able to start
running again right away!
（砂の里の忍）
少し休憩させてください
Please let us rest a little while.
あっ だらしないぞ
You guys have no discipline.
And you call yourselves Shinobi?!
それでも お前ら忍か！
Stop being unreasonable.
（カンクロウ）無理 言うじゃん
こいつらだって
24時間 交代での国境警備
These guys took turns guarding
the border for a whole day.
そのまま里へ とんぼ返りしたうえ
ここまで走ってきたんだ
And no sooner had they returned
to the village,
they had to run all the way here...
どんな優秀な忍だって
これ以上は 無理させられないじゃん
However top-notch Shinobi they may be,
you can't force them to do
more than this.
No, we're okay!
いえ 大丈夫です
We can't be resting while
Gaara-sama is in trouble!
我愛羅様が ピンチのときに
休んでなんかいられません
（砂の里の忍）あっ
風影かぜかげ様のために
俺たちが 今できることを
We should do what we can
for the Kazekage-sama's sake!
そうだ 風影様のために
Yes, for the Kazekage-sama's sake!
テマリさん 出発しましょう
Temari-san! Let's head out.
お前ら よく言ってくれた
You guys! That's the spirit!
（エビゾウ）
まあ そう熱くなるでない
Now, now,
you shouldn't get so fired up about it.
（テマリ）エビゾウじい様
Grandfather Ebizo...
（エビゾウ）
忍たるもの いかなるときも
冷静さを失ってはならんのよ
A Shinobi should never lose
his composure under any circumstances.
それを忘れ １人深追いしたのは
今回のカンクロウの失敗
Forgetting that and pursuing
the enemy too far all by himself
was the cause of
Kankuro's recent failure, wasn't it?
違うか？
（カンクロウ）ハッハハ
それに 今のお前たちは
まるで周りが見えておらん
Besides, in your current state,
all of you are not being aware
of your surroundings.
それは 一体…
What do you mean by that...?
まあ あれを見てみろ
Well, look at that.
（テマリ）ん？
（マツリ）あっ あれは
Th-That...?!
（エビゾウ）恐らくは
木こノ葉はと暁あかつきが やり合った跡だろうよ
That must be the remains of the battle
that Akatsuki fought with the Leaf.
（テマリ）あっ それでは…
That means...
（エビゾウ）そうじゃ
Yes. You have to assume that
we have already entered their territory.
わしらは すでにヤツらの
テリトリーの中に入ったと
考えるべきじゃろう
これより先 どんなトラップが
仕掛けてあるかも分からん
There's no telling what kind of traps
they may have set up ahead.
そんな場所へ
足を踏み入れようとしとるときに
When you're about to set foot
in such a place,
今のお主らのように
疲れきった状態で飛び込んでみろ
you'll be annihilated in no time
if you go dashing in,
あっという間に全滅よ
exhausted the way you all are now.
（２人）あっ
あっ
あっ…
ちょうどよい
This is just perfect.
休憩がてら
わしが 昔話でもしてやろう
While you're resting, I'll tell you all
a story about the old days.
あれは ずいぶん昔のことよ
It was long, long ago.
お主らも
耳にしたことぐらいはあるじゃろ
I'm sure you must
have heard of it...
三代目風影の事件は
The incident of the Third Kazekage.
ん あっ 三代目風影
The Third... Kazekage?
ああ 先々代の風影よ
Yes... The one before
the previous Kazekage.
三代目は 歴代風影の中でも
最強とうたわれておった
Of all the Kazekage
down through history,
the Third Kazekage was
said to be the most powerful.
その三代目が 何者かに
さらわれるという事件が起き
Then the incident occurred when
someone kidnapped the Kazekage.
里中が躍起になり
三代目の消息を追った
The entire village got all excited
and went out seeking news
of what had become
of the Third...
今にして思えば
Looking back upon it now,
冷静さを欠いておったとしか
言いようがない
you would have to say
that they simply lost their cool.
里の守りは 手薄となり
The village's guard wore thin,
allowing the enemy to intrude,
and panic ensued.
敵の侵入を許し 混乱した
あのとき
もう少し冷静に対処しておれば
If they had dealt with it
a little more coolly at the time,
その後の戦争も
回避できたろうによ
the subsequent war
could have been avoided.
I am painfully aware of how
you all feel right now...
今のお主らの気持ちは
痛いほど よく分かる
じゃが だからといって
But... you mustn't repeat
the same mistakes
三代目のときと同じような過ちを
繰り返してはならぬのよ
that were made back in
the days of the Third.
エビゾウ様
Ebizo-sama...
それで その後
三代目の消息はつかめたのですか？
did they ever learn what happened to
the Third Kazekage after that?
あれから暗部あんぶが
ひそかに調査を続けてはおるが
After that, the Anbu Black Ops
continued to investigate in secret,
but no body was ever found,
遺体はおろか 移動した痕跡すら
いまだ出てこんのだ
nor any sign that the Kazekage
had been removed...
What's wrong, Grandmother Chiyo?
（サソリ）どうした？ チヨバア様
Are you so filled with emotion
that you cannot speak?
感激のあまり声も出ないか？
無理もない
20年ぶりの再会だからな
That's not surprising.
After all, it's our first reunion
in 20 years.
（チヨ）サソリ お主
Sasori, you...
（サソリ）ついでだ
とっておきを見せてやる
While I'm at it,
I'll show you something special.
感激すること請け合いだぜ
It's guaranteed to move you.
殺すとき 苦労したコレクションだが
A collection that gave me
a hard time when trying to kill it, but...
“三”？
Three?
それだけに いちばん気に入っている
That's why I like this best of all.
そ… それは
Th-That... It couldn't be!
まさか！
何？ どうしたんです？
What? What's wrong?!
それは… 三代目風影
That's... the Third Kazekage...
えっ？
What?!
三代目風影
The Third... Kazekage?
フフフ…
How about it?
どうだ？
懐かしいだろ チヨバア
Doesn't that take you back,
Grandma Chiyo?
チヨバア様 三代目風影って…
Grandmother Chiyo, the Third Kazekage...?
How could this have happened?
なんたることじゃ
それじゃあ
Then...
It was over ten years ago
（チヨ）もう10年以上も前じゃ
that the Third suddenly
disappeared from the village.
三代目が突然 里から消えたのは
（サクラ）はっ…
（チヨ）八方 手を尽くしたのじゃが
とうとう見つからなんだ
We scoured the countryside,
but we were never able to find him.
最強の風影じゃったが
He was the most powerful
of all the Kazekage's, but...
サソリ お前が…
Sasori, you...?
And so what if I did?
だったら どうした？
Do you mean to say that a retired
old grandma with one foot in the grave
隠居した死にかけのババアが
三代目の敵討ちでもするってのか？
is about to avenge the Third?
Tough luck...
ご苦労なこった
（チヨ）隠居の死にかけでも
わざわざ重い腰を上げてみるもんじゃ
Retired, with one foot in the grave.
That may be so,
but it was worth hauling
my heavy behind over here.
まだまだ
死ぬには心残りがありすぎる
I'd have too many regrets
if I were to die now.
わが孫が 悪党に
身を落とすだけならまだしも
It's bad enough that my grandson
got himself mixed up
with a bad crowd...
but to think that you'd betray the village
里を裏切り ３度までも
風影に手をかけようとは
and try to meddle with the Kazekage,
for the third time!
“３度”？
Third time?
It was Orochimaru
who killed Gaara's father,
（チヨ）我愛羅の父 四代目風影を
殺したのは大蛇丸(おろちまる)じゃったが
the Fourth Kazekage, but...
それを手引きしたのは こヤツじゃ
the one who guided them
was Sasori!
そして 今回の我愛羅も
And this time,
Gaara and even the Third...
さらには三代目まで
（サソリ）おいおい
四代目つうのは 俺は知らねえぜ
Hey, hey, I don't know
anything about the Fourth.
手引きは 俺の部下がやったことだ
The one who guided them
was my subordinate.
In that case, it's the same
as if you did it yourself.
ならば お前がやったのも
同じじゃろうが
関係ないと言うのか
Can you really say that
you were not involved?
（サソリ）確かに 暁では
Indeed, I was originally paired with
Orochimaru back at the Akatsuki,
もともと大蛇丸と組んでたから
いろいろやったが
so I did lots of things but...
あっ…
あなたは…
You...
あなた 大蛇丸と組んでたってことは
If you were paired
with Orochimaru...
大蛇丸のことを
then that means you know
about Orochimaru.
くっ…
In that case, there're a lot
of questions I need you to answer!
なら いろいろと聞きたいことがあるわ
（サソリ）フッ
（チヨ）サクラ…
Sakura...
あいにくだったな
Unfortunately,
I must take you two out
俺は お前らを片づけて
さっきの人柱力を
捕まえなきゃならない
and go capture that Jinchuriki.
人を待たせるのは 嫌いなもんでね
I hate to keep people waiting,
質問に答えてる時間はない
so I have no time
to answer your questions.
さて…
So...
shall we get right to it?
もうやるか
（サクラ）来る
Here it comes!
うっ…
（チヨの掛け声）
（サクラ）ああっ…
死ね！
Die!
（サクラ）うっ
（チヨ）速い！
He's fast!
ヒルコの尾が バラバラとは
To think that Hiruko's tail
fell to pieces...
やるなチヨバア
You've got some
pretty good moves, Grandma Chiyo.
In that case, how about this?
なら これでどうだ
ああ… いかん
Oh no!
そらあ！
Take this!
サクラ！
Sakura!
（サソリ）ちっ 仕損じたか
Damn. Did I botch it?
（サクラ）はあ 助かった
Saved!
With the old grandma manipulating things,
it's impossible to get anywhere.
（サソリ）ババアが操ってんなら
らちが明かねえ
（サクラ）あっ
In that case...
だったら…
あっ
いかん！ サクラ息を止めろ！
Oh, no! Sakura! Hold your breath!
（サクラ）毒…
Is it poison?!
In this poisonous smoke,
your movements will be irrelevant.
（サソリ）
毒煙なら 動きは関係ねえぜ
Sakura--!
サクラ！
♪～
Just like always.
daitai itsumo doori ni
As I turn that corner.
sono kado wo magareba
I am lost in the waves of people.
hitonami ni magire komi
Melting, disappearing.
tokete kiete iku
I lose my way.
boku wa michi wo nakushi
I even completely lose my words.
kotoba suranaku shite shimau
But just one thing.
dakedo hitotsu dake wa
Remained, remained.
nokotteta nokotteta
Your voice.
kimi no koe ga
Your smiling faces, your angry faces, everything.
warau kao mo okaru kao mo subete
Keeps me walking on.
boku wo arukaseru
Surely, when I see the point where the clouds have broken.
kumo ga kireta saki wo mitara kitto nee
You know what I mean?
wakaru desho
nee wakaru desho
～♪
Next Episode
Guy-sensei, this is terrible!
大変です ガイ先生
What is it, Lee?!
どうした？ リーよ
According to the information
received just now,
今 入った情報によると
きょうのミニコーナーの主役は
カカシ先生だそうです
Kakashi-sensei is the star
of today's Mini Feature!
なんだと！
What?! He gets a juicy deal like that
while we're down here fighting?!
俺たちが戦ってる間に
そんな おいしい企画を
こうなったら さっさと片づけて
In that case,
we'll have to take these guys out
quickly and join the show!
僕たちも
参加するしかありませんね
Youth at full power!
青春フルパワーだ！
No way, we can't make it...
間に合うものか
Hard effort will pay off!
Right, Tenten?
なせば成る なあテンテンよ
あれ？ テンテンは？
Huh? Where's Tenten?!
ＭＣに抜てきされたって
She just left all excited,
saying she got selected as the MC!
さっき 張り切って出てった
なんですと！
Say what--?! That traitor!
Chiyo's Secret Skills
この裏切り者め！
Notable People in the Leaf Village
Notable People in the Leaf Village!
やっほ～
Hi there, this comer is all about
introducing the village's famous people.
里の有名人を紹介する このコーナー
今回 紹介するのは
This time, we're going to introduce
the Leaf's Number One Tactician,
木ノ葉一の業師 はたけカカシ先生
Hatake Kakashi-sensei.
That was the idea, but...
he hasn't shown up yet, has he?
…なんだけど
まだ来てないのよね
A guy who would keep a lady waiting
is the worst!
女性を待たせるなんて最低
うわっ
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
（カカシ）どうも
やっと来た もう
You finally got here. Good grief!
Sorry, sorry...
（カカシ）やあ すまん すまん
とにかくゲストも来たし
改めて 紹介いってみよう！
— Anyway, our guest has arrived.
— Today I was tossed around by...
— So let's formally introduce him!
— the harsh waves of life... Hey listen!
He's the captain of Squad 7,
consisting of Naruto, Sasuke, and Sakura,
ナルト サスケ サクラの
第７班の隊長で
木ノ葉でも トップクラスの実力者
and one of the Leafs top-rated ninja.
He's the only one outside of
the Uchiha clan to possess a Sharingan,
うちは一族以外で
唯一 写輪眼しゃりんがんを持ち
相手の術を
写し取ってしまうことから
and due to it's ability to duplicate
his opponent's jutsu,
付いた呼び名が…
he gained the title of
“The Monkey See, Monkey Do Guy”.
No, don't you mean the “Copy Ninja”?
（カカシ）
じゃなくて…
…でしょ
（テンテン）
そんなカカシ先生の
唯一のオリジナルにして
And of such, Kakashi-sensei's
one and only original
and most powerful jutsu is,
最強の術こそが 奥義千年殺せんねんごろし
Secret Finger Jutsu:
One Thousand Years of Death!
（カカシ）違～う 雷切(らいきり)だ 雷切
No, it isn't! It's Lightning Blade!
Lightning Blade!
Hey Tenten, is it just me,
（カカシ）もう ちょっとテンテン
or am I the only one
who's getting bad treatment?
俺だけ扱いひどくない？
そ～んなこと
ないですよ
That's not true!
アッハハハ…